Count the money. Count it again. Count on no one.
The Rip is a action, thriller, crime film directed by Joe Carnahan.
Trust frays when a team of Miami cops discovers millions in cash inside a run-down
stash house, calling everyone — and everything — into question.
Lieutenant Dane Dumars, played by Matt Damon.
Detective Sergeant J.D. Byrne, played by Ben Affleck.
Detective Mike Ro, played by Steven Yeun.
Detective Numa Baptistie, played by Teyana Taylor.
Detective Lolo Salazar, played by Catalina Sandino Moreno.
Desiree 'Desi' Lopez Molina, played by Sasha Calle.
The Rip is a 2026 American action thriller film written and directed by
Joe Carnahan who developed the story with Michael McGrale.
The film stars Matt Damon and Ben Affleck as police officers within
the narcotics unit of the Miami-Dade Police Department.
It also stars Steven Yeun, Teyana Taylor, Sasha Calle, Catalina
Sandino Moreno, Scott Adkins, and Kyle Chandler.
The film is inspired by the true story of
Miami-Dade County Sheriff Chris Casiano.
This film tells the story of a group of police officers who, during a raid on a hidden cash operation, find
their trust broken down as team members suspect each other of trying to steal a large sum of cash.
It was released by Netflix on January 16, 2026, to
generally favorable reviews from critics.
The production company, Artist Equity, negotiated a first of its kind deal with Netflix that provides the workers
involved in the production of the film with a bonus if it performs well on the streaming platform.
The film explores themes of miami, florida, police, dirty cop, trust, angry.
The tone is intense.